Ernest Abah

Software Engineer

Everyday I work on intelligent web applications and build highly optimized algorithms that give customers the very best user experience. If at the end of each day, users can rate my software as fast, secure and reliable, then my work is done.

■ abahernesto@gmail.com

Lagos, Nigeria

in linkedin.com/in/abahernest

2349078780658

abahernest-portfolio.herokuapp.com

github.com/abahernest

PROJECT EXPERIENCES

COVID-19 IMPACT APIDjango Rest Framework

04/2020

As the name suggests, it's an Application Programming Interface that estimates the impact of the Covid-19 pandemic on economies of the world based on statistical data from WHO and UNESCO.

Link to project

https://damp-everglades-17968.herokuapp.com/api/v1/on-covid-19/

SHREDFULL

Django/colourlib templates/PostgreSQL

02/2020 - Present

Shredfull is an all-fitness consultation web application that provides access to fitness service providers in my college (UNILAG) so that they can be easily accessed by customers at their convenience.

Link to project

https://shredfull.herokuapp.com

WORK EXPERIENCES

Program MentorALC with Microsoft

05/2020 - Present

Achievements

 Invited by Andela (a talent recruitment and development company) to mentor students who were undertaking training for Azure Fundamentals Certification. Improved student's engagement with study content and provided alternative learning and

Lagos, Ng

Lagos, NG

test resources which increased comprehension of study materials

SKILLS

Data Structures and algorithms

Django

Flask

Git

SQL

Software Testing

EDUCATION

University of Lagos. BSc. Computer Engineering (2017 – 2021)

- 2X Recipient of Total E&P Undergraduate Scholarship
- 2X Recipient of MTN Technology Undergraduate Scholarship

LEADERSHIP

Head, Membership Committee, IEEE SB UNILAG (05/2020 – Present)

Campus Ambassador, TechBridge Consulting (05/2020 – Present)

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python

Professional Working Proficiency

Javascript

Professional Working Proficiency

C++

Professional Working Proficiency

Hackathon ContestantPayAsYouKnow Hackathon

03/2020

Achievements

 Emerged Top 20 in the nationwide hackathon organised by FSI in partnership with The Central Bank of Nigeria to tackle fraud and innovate payment systems. Developed a web application that serves as a central hub for Payment of value added services and incorporated deep learning models to detect fraudulent transactions.